1.If the probability of event A is 0.7, what is the probability of the complement of A?
1-0.7=0.3

2. Suppose you have a deck of 52 playing cards. What is the probability of drawing either a red card or a face card (jack, queen, or king)?
26/52+12/52-6/52=1/2-1/4-3/26=0.61

3. In a group of 120 students, 65 are enrolled in a math class, 45 in a physics class, and 30 in both. What is the probability that a randomly selected student is enrolled in either the math or physics class?
65+45-30=80
80/A U B=80/120=2/3=0.66

4. A fair six-sided die is rolled twice. What is the probability of getting a 4 on the first roll and an even number on the second roll?
set=1,2,3,4,5,6
set
1 2 3 4 5 6=1/6
2 4 6=3/6
1/2*1/6=1/12

5. In a factory, 80% of the products pass quality control. If 90% of the defective products trigger an alarm, what is the probability that a randomly selected product triggers the alarm and is defective?
0.2*(0.9)=0.18

6. If P(B)=0.4 and P(C)=0.6, and B and C are mutually exclusive events, what is the probability of B∪C?
1 

8. A survey finds that 60% of people like chocolate (event C), and 40% like vanilla (event V). What is the probability that a randomly chosen person likes either chocolate or vanilla?
1

9. In a group of students, 70% play basketball (event B) and 40% play soccer (event S). If 30% of the students play both sports, what is the probability that a student chosen at random plays both basketball and soccer?
0.7+0.4-0.3=0.8


10. A factory produces two types of products, A and B. The probability of a randomly selected product being of type A is 0.7, and the probability of it being of type B is 0.4. Are the events of selecting a type A product and a type B product independent?
0.7*0.4=0.28

11. In a deck of cards, two cards are drawn without replacement. If the first card drawn is a king, what is the probability that the second card drawn is also a king?


(3/51)/(4/52)=(1/17)/(1/13)=13/17=0.76



